Bryce Lim

DKFZ German Cancer Research Centre · Im Neuenheimer Feld 280 · 69120 Heidelberg · Germany Phone (DE): +49 176 32125172 · Email: <u>b.lim@dkfz.de</u>

PERSONAL PROFILE

I am a highly motivated researcher with an interest in cell fate and cancer biology. I have experience in a wide variety of laboratory techniques, including *in vitro* plate-based biochemical assays, protein expression and analysis, and tissue culture. I am proficient in using specialist software and writing scripts to generate, manage, and analyse large and complex datasets.

EDUCATION

German Cancer Research Centre (DKFZ), University of Heidelberg, PhD — 2019-Present

Molecular determinants of cell fate

University of Cambridge, MSci in Biochemistry — 2018-2019

- Cell Fate
- Contemporary Cancer Studies

University of Cambridge, BA (Hons) in Natural Sciences - 2015-2018

1st Year2nd Year3rd Year• Biology of Cells• Biochemistry and Molecular Biology• Biochemistry

Physiology

Physiology of Organisms

• Chemistry

Mathematical Biology

• History and Philosophy of Science

Chinese International School of Hong Kong, International Baccalaureate Diploma — 2011-2014

• Higher Level: Chemistry, Biology, Mathematics

• Standard Level: History, English Literature, Chinese ab initio

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

PhD, Mall Lab, German Cancer Research Institute (DKFZ), Heidelberg, Germany — Sep 2019-Present

Investigation of terminal repressor transcription factors and their role in cell fate specification during transdifferentiation in Dr Moritz Mall's lab.

Master of Science Project Student, Markowetz Lab, Cancer Research UK Cambridge Institute — Oct 2018-Mar 2019

Identification of structural variation signatures in paired ovarian cancer cell lines and a comparison of these with established copy number signatures in ovarian cancer with Dr Andrew Holding in Florian Markowetz's lab.

• Human tissue culture, Hi-C, library preparation for Illumina sequencing, Hi-C data analysis and presentation

Intern Scientist, Cancer Research UK Therapeutic Discovery Laboratory, Cambridge, UK - Jul-Sep 2018

Developed a kinetic ATPase assay for testing compounds against enzyme targets as part of a key Alliance project.

- Kinetic assay development and optimisation in FI, FP, and FRET plate-based formats
- Detailed data analysis using GraphPad Prism; presentation of work to core Screening and Compound Profiling team

Final Year Project Student, Silva Lab, Cambridge Stem Cell Institute, Cambridge, UK — Jan-Mar 2018

Investigated the influence of various pluripotency-related genes upon STAT3 signalling in transfected mouse embryonic stem cells in Dr José Silva's lab.

Mouse ESC tissue culture, cell line management, Tet-on gene induction, Western blotting, RT-qPCR

Summer Intern, Thornton Lab, EMBL-EBI, Hinxton, UK - Jun-Sep 2017

Generated a database of designed (de novo) enzymes in Prof Janet Thornton's lab.

- · Chemical formula encoding using SMILES and .mol files, and mechanism encoding using .rxn files
- Data manipulation, management, and analysis using Python, RDKit, EC-BLAST, and Reaction Decoder Tool

Technical Assistant, Tanner Lab, Biochemistry Dept., University of Hong Kong — Oct 2014-Sep 2015

Developed a malaria rapid diagnostic test and droplet sorting device in Dr Julian Tanner's lab.

- Protein expression: sterile techniques, cell culture, FPLC, SDS-PAGE, Western blotting
- Microfluidic rapid diagnostic test design and printing: 3D CAD and stereolithography
- Directed evolution of DNA aptamers (SELEX)
- Enzyme-linked assays: Magnetic bead-based aptamer-tethered enzyme capture, gold nanoparticle competitive assays, DNAzyme selection through fluorescence activated droplet sorting

PUBLICATIONS

Fraser, L. A., Kinghorn, A. B., Dirkzwager, R. M., Liang, S., Cheung, Y. W., **Lim, B.**, Shiu, S. C. C., Tang, M. S., Andrew, D., Manitta, J., Richards, J. S. and Tanner, J. A. A Portable Microfluidic Aptamer Tethered Enzyme Capture (APTEC) Biosensor for Malaria Diagnosis. *Biosensors and Bioelectronics* 100 (2018): 591-596.

Fraser, L.A., Kinghorn, A.B., Tang, M.S., Cheung, Y.W., **Lim, B.**, Liang, S., Dirkzwager, R.M. and Tanner, J.A. Oligonucleotide Functionalised Microbeads: Indispensable Tools for High-Throughput Aptamer Selection. *Molecules* 20, no. 12 (2015): 21298-21312.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Summer Teacher, Kelly Yang Project, Hong Kong - Jun-Aug 2016

Taught English to students 5-16 years old; created lesson plans for Model UN and debate

Private Tutor, IB Middle Years Program, Hong Kong — Sep 2014-Aug 2015

Tutored students in years 8 and 9 in mathematics, biology, chemistry, physics, and English

SKILLS

Programming and Markup	Proficient in Python: basic knowledge of R. Matlab, and Java: proficient in HTML and CSS	٥.
Programming and Markup	Proficient in Python, basic knowledge of R. Matiab, and Java, proficient in Filivic and CSS	٥.

proficient with git and the command line

Specialist Applications HiCUP, Homer Tools, PyMol, RDKit, ChEBI API, EC-BLAST, Reaction Decoder Tool,

ImageJ, GraphPad Prism

CATIA, Autodesk Fusion 360, Autodesk Inventor, Blender, and ASIGA software

CO-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

Fitzwilliam College Natural President 2017-18; organised academic and social events for members. Sciences Society

Athletics Fitzwilliam College Athletics Captain 2018-2019. University Sprints Squad Captain

2018-2019. Member of Cambridge University Athletics Club and Achilles Club. Member of

2018 and 2019 Varsity Match teams.

Football Fitzwilliam College 2nd team; 2017 League and Cup champions.

Cancer Awareness in Teenagers Society College representative; raised funds and organised events to raise awareness of cancer in teenagers and young people.

REFERENCES

Dr Moritz Mall	Dr Holly C. Canuto	Dr Julian Tanner	Dr José Silva
Group Leader	Director of Studies	Associate Professor	Group Leader
German Cancer Research	Fitzwilliam College	Department of Biochemistry	Wellcome-MRC Stem Cell
Centre (DKFZ)	Storey's Way	University of Hong Kong	Institute
Im Neuenheimer Feld 280	University of Cambridge	L3-70, Laboratory Block	University of Cambridge
69120 Heidelberg	Cambridge, CB3 0DG	21 Sassoon Road	Tennis Court Road, CB2 1QR
Germany	United Kingdom	Hong Kong	United Kingdom
(+49) 06221 423195	(+44) 01223 768487	(+852) 3917 9472	(+44) 1223 760240
m.mall@dkfz.de	hcc36@cam.ac.uk	jatanner@hku.hk	ics64@cscr.cam.ac.uk